<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on Drew DeVault&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>./tags/security.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on Drew DeVault&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="./tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rotating passwords in bulk in the wake of security events</title>
      <link>./2017/05/11/Rotating-passwords.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2017/05/11/Rotating-passwords.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting this post off for a while. Do you remember the CloudFlare security problem that happened a few months ago? This is the one that disclosed huge amounts of sensitive information for huge numbers websites. When this happened, your accounts on thousands of websites were potentially compromised.
Updating passwords for all of these services at once was a major source of frustration for users. Updating a single password can take 5 minutes, and changing dozens of them might take hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSG_PEEK is pretty common, CVE-2016-10229 is worse than you think</title>
      <link>./2017/04/13/MSG_PEEK-is-more-common-than-you-think-CVE-2016-10229.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2017/04/13/MSG_PEEK-is-more-common-than-you-think-CVE-2016-10229.html</guid>
      <description>I heard about CVE-2016-10229 earlier today. In a nutshell, it allows for arbitrary code execution via UDP traffic if userspace programs are using MSG_PEEK in their recv calls. I quickly updated my kernels and rebooted any boxes where necessary, but when I read the discussions on this matter I saw people downplaying this issue by claiming MSG_PEEK is an obscure feature.
I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be a fear monger and I&amp;rsquo;m by no means a security expert but I suspect that this is a deeply incorrect conclusion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
