<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fiction on Drew DeVault&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>./tags/fiction.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in fiction on Drew DeVault&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="./tags/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The last years</title>
      <link>./2018/02/13/The-last-years.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2018/02/13/The-last-years.html</guid>
      <description>August 14th, 2019 PYONGYANG IN CHAOS AS PANDEMIC DECIMATES LEADERSHIP. Sources within the country have reported that a fast-acting and deadly infectious disease has suddenly infected the population of Pyongyang, the capital city of North Korea, where most of the country&amp;rsquo;s political elite live. Unconfirmed reports suggest that a significant fraction of the leadership has been affected.
The reclusive country has appealed for immediate aid from the international community and it is reported that a group of medical experts from Seoul have been permitted to enter via the Joint Security Area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A history of emergent intelligence</title>
      <link>./2017/12/02/History-of-intelligent-observation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2017/12/02/History-of-intelligent-observation.html</guid>
      <description>As you all know, the simulation of universe 2813/9301 is now coming to a close. This simulation is notable for being the first simulated universe suitable for hosting intelligent life, but yesterday the simulation reached a state where we believe no additional intelligences will emerge. It seems the final state of this set of physical laws is a dark and empty universe of slowly evaporating black holes. Though, given the historical significance of this simulation, it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely we we&amp;rsquo;ll be turning it off any time soon!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
