<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>video on Drew DeVault&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>./tags/video.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in video on Drew DeVault&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="./tags/video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Webcast: Reviewing git &amp; mercurial patches with email</title>
      <link>./2019/05/13/Git-email-webcast.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/05/13/Git-email-webcast.html</guid>
      <description>With the availability of new resources like git-send-email.io, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on making the email-based workflow more understandable and accessible to the world. One thing that&amp;rsquo;s notably missing from this tutorial, however, is the maintainer side of the work. I intend to do a full write-up in the future, but for now I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be helpful to clarify my workflow a bit with a short webcast. In this video, I narrate my workflow as I review a few sourcehut patches and participate in some dicsussions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[VIDEO] Arch Linux with full disk encryption in (about) 15 minutes</title>
      <link>./2016/08/18/Arch-Linux-with-full-disk-encryption-in-15-minutes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2016/08/18/Arch-Linux-with-full-disk-encryption-in-15-minutes.html</guid>
      <description>window.HELP_IMPROVE_VIDEOJS = false;   After my blog post emphasizing the importance of taking control of your privacy, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to make a few more posts going over detailed instructions on how to actually do so. Today we have a video that goes over the process of installing Arch Linux with full disk encryption.
This is my first go at publishing videos on my blog, so please provide some feedback in the comments of this article.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
