<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>practices on Drew DeVault&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>./tags/practices.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in practices on Drew DeVault&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="./tags/practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add a &#34;contrib&#34; directory to your projects</title>
      <link>./2020/06/06/Add-a-contrib-directory.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2020/06/06/Add-a-contrib-directory.html</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a common pattern among free- and open-source software projects to include a &amp;ldquo;contrib&amp;rdquo; directory at the top of their source code tree. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this in many projects for many years, but I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it discussed only rarely — so here we are!
The contrib directory is used as an unorganized (or, at best, lightly organized) bin of various useful things contributed by the community around the software, but which is not necessarily a good candidate for being a proper part of the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers shouldn&#39;t distribute their own software</title>
      <link>./2019/12/09/Developers-shouldnt-distribute.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/12/09/Developers-shouldnt-distribute.html</guid>
      <description>An oft-heard complaint about Linux is that software distribution often takes several forms: a Windows version, a macOS version, and&amp;hellip; a Debian version, an Ubuntu version, a Fedora version, a CentOS version, an openSUSE version&amp;hellip; but these complaints miss the point. The true distributable form for Linux software, and rather for Unix software in general, is a .tar.gz file containing the source code.
Note: This article presumes that proprietary/nonfree software is irrelevant, and so should you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fuck up software releases</title>
      <link>./2019/10/12/how-to-fuck-up-releases.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/10/12/how-to-fuck-up-releases.html</guid>
      <description>I manage releases for a bunch of free &amp;amp; open-source software. Just about every time I ship a release, I find a novel way to fuck it up. Enough of these fuck-ups have accumulated now that I wanted to share some of my mistakes and how I (try to) prevent them from happening twice.
At first, I did everything manually. This is fine enough for stuff with simple release processes - stuff that basically amounts to tagging a commit, pushing it, and calling it a day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
