<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sourcehut on Drew DeVault&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>./tags/sourcehut.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in sourcehut on Drew DeVault&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="./tags/sourcehut/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building interactive SSH applications</title>
      <link>./2019/09/02/Interactive-SSH-programs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/09/02/Interactive-SSH-programs.html</guid>
      <description>After the announcement of [shell access for builds.sr.ht jobs]builds announcement, a few people sent me some questions, wondering how this sort of thing is done. Writing interactive SSH applications is actually pretty easy, but it does require some knowledge of the pieces involved and a little bit of general Unix literacy.
On the server, there are three steps which you can meddle with using OpenSSH: authentication, the shell session, and the command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell access for builds.sr.ht CI</title>
      <link>./2019/08/19/Introducing-shell-access-for-builds.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/08/19/Introducing-shell-access-for-builds.html</guid>
      <description>Have you ever found yourself staring at a failed CI build, wondering desperately what happened? Or, have you ever needed a fresh machine on-demand to test out an idea in? Have you been working on Linux, but need to test something on OpenBSD? Starting this week, builds.sr.ht can help with all of these problems, because you can now SSH into the build environment.
If you didn&#39;t know, Sourcehut is the 100% open/libre software forge for hackers, complete with git and Mercurial hosting, CI, mailing lists, and more - with no JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing code annotations for SourceHut</title>
      <link>./2019/07/08/Announcing-annotations-for-sourcehut.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/07/08/Announcing-annotations-for-sourcehut.html</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that code annotations are now available for SourceHut! These allow you to decorate your code with arbitrary links and markdown. The end result looks something like this:
NOTICE: Annotations were ultimately removed from sourcehut.
SourceHut is the &#34;hacker&#39;s forge&#34;, a 100% open-source platform for hosting Git &amp;amp; Mercurial repos, bug trackers, mailing lists, continuous integration, and more. No JavaScript required!  The annotations shown here are sourced from a JSON file which you can generate and upload during your CI process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a fork, really, and how GitHub changed its meaning</title>
      <link>./2019/05/24/What-is-a-fork.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/05/24/What-is-a-fork.html</guid>
      <description>The fork button on GitHub - with the little number next to it for depositing dopamine into your brain - is a bit misleading. GitHub co-opted the meaning of &amp;ldquo;fork&amp;rdquo; to trick you into participating in their platform more. They did this in a well-intentioned way, for the sake of their pull requests feature, but ultimately this design is self-serving and causes some friction when contributors venture out of their GitHub sandbox and into the rest of the software development ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing first-class Mercurial support on Sourcehut</title>
      <link>./2019/04/15/Announcing-first-class-hg-support-on-sourcehut.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/04/15/Announcing-first-class-hg-support-on-sourcehut.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce that the final pieces have fallen into place for Mercurial support on SourceHut, which is now on-par with our git offering. Special thanks are owed to SourceHut contributor Ludovic Chabant, who has been instrumental in adding Mercurial support to SourceHut. You may have heard about it while this was still experimental - but I&amp;rsquo;m happy to tell you that we have now completely integrated Mercurial support into SourceHut!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourcehut&#39;s spartan approach to web design</title>
      <link>./2019/03/04/sourcehut-design.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/03/04/sourcehut-design.html</guid>
      <description>Sourcehut is known for its brutalist design, with its mostly shades-of-gray appearance, conservative color usage, and minimal distractions throughout. This article aims to share some insights into the philosophy that guides this design, both for the curious reader and for the new contributor to the open-source project.
The most important principle is that sr.ht is an engineering tool first and foremost, and when you&amp;rsquo;re there it&amp;rsquo;s probably because you&amp;rsquo;re in engineering mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I chose Flask to build sr.ht&#39;s mini-services</title>
      <link>./2019/01/30/Why-I-built-sr.ht-with-Flask.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/01/30/Why-I-built-sr.ht-with-Flask.html</guid>
      <description>sr.ht is a large, production-scale suite of web applications (I call them &amp;ldquo;mini-services&amp;rdquo;, as they strike a balance between microservices and monolithic applications) which are built in Python with Flask. David Lord, one of the maintainers of Flask, reached out to me when he heard about sr.ht and saw that it was built with Flask. At his urging, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share the rationale behind the decision and how it&amp;rsquo;s turned out in the long run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backups &amp; redundancy at sr.ht</title>
      <link>./2019/01/13/Backups-and-redundancy-at-sr.ht.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2019/01/13/Backups-and-redundancy-at-sr.ht.html</guid>
      <description>sr.ht1 is 100% open source and I encourage people to install it on their own infrastructure, especially if they&amp;rsquo;ll be sending patches upstream. However, I am equally thrilled to host sr.ht for you on the &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; instance, and most users find this useful because the maintenance burden is non-trivial. Today I&amp;rsquo;ll give you an idea of what your subscription fee pays for. In this first post on ops at sr.ht, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about backups and redundancy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sr.ht, the hacker&#39;s forge, now open for public alpha</title>
      <link>./2018/11/15/sr.ht-general-availability.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2018/11/15/sr.ht-general-availability.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce today that I&amp;rsquo;m opening sr.ht (pronounced &amp;ldquo;sir hat&amp;rdquo;, or any other way you want) to the general public for the remainder of the alpha period. Though it&amp;rsquo;s missing some of the features which will be available when it&amp;rsquo;s completed, sr.ht today represents a very capable software forge which is already serving the needs of many projects in the free &amp;amp; open source software community. If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with the project and ready to register your account, you can head straight to the sign up page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should you move from GitHub to sr.ht</title>
      <link>./2018/06/05/Should-you-move-to-sr.ht.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./2018/06/05/Should-you-move-to-sr.ht.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not terribly concerned about Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s acquisition of GitHub, but I don&amp;rsquo;t fault those who are worried. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on my alternative platform, sr.ht, for quite a while. I&amp;rsquo;m not about to leave GitHub because of Microsoft alone. I do have some political disagreements with GitHub and Microsoft, but those are also not the main reason that I&amp;rsquo;m building sr.ht. I simply think I can do it better. If my approach aligns with your needs, then sr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
